Guide to the Robert J. Smith papers, 1950-2005.
Smith, Robert J. Papers, 1950-2005
- Series XXI. Suye-Mura Material
  - Wiswell/Smith Correspondence, 1965-1981 (Box 46, Folder 1)
  - Wiswell/Smith Correspondence, 1982-1983 (Box 46, Folder 2)
  - Wiswell/Smith Correspondence, 1984-1986 (Box 46, Folder 3)
  - Wiswell/Smith Correspondence, 1987-1988 (Box 46, Folder 4)
  - Wiswell/Smith Correspondence, 1989-1992 (Box 46, Folder 5)
  - Wiswell/Smith Correspondence, 1993-1995 (Box 46, Folder 6)
  - Wiswell/Smith Correspondence & Ella L. Wiswell Obituary, 1996-2005 (Box 46, Folder 7)
  - The following folders contain Ella L. Wiswell's correspondence with a variety of individuals and institutions. Most of the correspondence concerns the 1935-1936 study of the Japanese village of Suye Mura conducted with her first husband John Fee Embree and her subsequent visits there in 1951 (following his death in 1950) and 1968 and 1985 with her second husband Frederic Wiswell.
  - University of Chicago Press, 1964-2002 (Box 46, Folder 8)
  - Reviews and Correspondence re: The Women of Suye Mura, Various (Box 46, Folder 9)
  - Kawamura Nozomu- Correspondence (Translator of The Women of Suye Mura), 1985-1988 (Box 46, Folder 10)
  - Publications on Suye Mura-various authors (Box 46, Folder 11)
  - Ushijima Morimitsu-Correspondence (Long time student of Suye Mura in the postwar period), 1959-1994 (Box 46, Folder 12)
  - Nishino Keisuke- Correspondence (Resident of Suye Mura and sponsor of 1985 celebration in Suye Mura. See much additional material.), 1985-1992 (Box 46, Folder 13)
  - Shirahama Tamotsu- Correspondence (Resident of Suye Mura.), 2000-2003 (Box 46, Folder 14)
  - Rudolf Janssen- Correspondence re: his paper on Occupation of Japan., 1992 (Box 46, Folder 15)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence., Various (Box 46, Folder 16)
  - Bulletin of Concerned Asia Scholars-Correspondence re: offensive issue., 1988 (Box 46, Folder 17)
  - Miscellaneous items concerning John Fee Embree following his death in 1950., 1950-1955 (Box 46, Folder 18)
  - First postwar visit to Suye Mura by Ella Lury Embree, 1951 (Box 46, Folder 19)
  - Second postwar visit to Suye Mura by Ella Lury and Fredric Wiswell, 1968 (Box 46, Folder 20)
  - Two Japanese Editions of Suye Mura: A Japanese Village by John F. Embree, 1939 (Box 46, Folder 21)
  - Ella Wiswell-Miscellaneous lectures on Japanese Women, Various (Box 46, Folder 22)
  - 50th Anniversary visit to Suye Mura by Ella Lury and Frederic Wiswell #1, 1985 (Box 47, Folder 1)
  - 50th Anniversary visit to Suye Mura by Ella Lury and Frederic Wiswell #2, 1985 (Box 47, Folder 2)
  - 50th Anniversary visit to Suye Mura by Ella Lury and Frederic Wiswell #3, 1985 (Box 47, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence-Japan Broadcasting Corporation (NHK), 1995 (Box 47, Folder 4)
  - Brochures- Suye Mura, Hitoyoshi Town, Kumamoto Prefecture, Various (Box 47, Folder 5)
  - Photograph album pages of Wiswells visit to Suye Mura, 1968 (Box 47, Folder 6)
  - Photograph album of 50th Anniversary Celebration, 1985 (Box 47, Folder 7)
  - 4 VHS tapes, Various (Box 47, Folder 8)
  - TKU: Women of the Village, 1994 (Box 47)
  - Wiswell/Smith Interview by David Plath, Honolulu, Hawaii I&II, 1995 (Box 47)
  - Hajiai to yasuragi no sato- Suye mura - Heisei 13- Heisei 15- Omoide no Kiseki, 2004 (Box 47)